# **Prateek Chatterjee**

<u>prateekpc.ux@gmail.com</u> - 508-471-0199 - <u>Portfolio</u> - <u>LinkedIn</u> - <u>YouTube</u> - Arlington, VA (*Willing to Relocate*)

I am a Senior Product Designer with five years of experience helping clients across the federal gov., healthcare, telecom, automotive and consulting industries. Successfully led projects, delivering user-centered solutions by understanding user needs, utilizing design thinking principles, fostering collaboration & incorporating iterative feedback.

- Design thinking
- Qualitative, quantitative res
- Visual, interaction design
- Competitive analysis
- A/B testing

- Design system
- Stakeholder mgmt
- 508 compliance testing
- Affinity mapping
- User interviews & surveys
- Managing UX team
- Wireframing, prototyping
- Usability testing
- User flows/personas/journeys
- Accessibility testing

#### **Professional Experience**

#### Senior Product Designer - CGI Inc. | March 2022 - Present

Received an Award in 2023 | Celebrating CGI's Values: Partnership and Quality

- Led complex digital products applications through multiple lifecycle and complex stakeholder management.
- Managed CGI's relationship with <u>Brightspeed Business</u>, leading design sprints with VP and marketing team to enhance customer acquisition, reducing customer attrition through improved CX with the launch of new products.
- Helped Brightspeed launch their brand online by migrating & redesigning 50+ webpages from Lumen and
  Centurylink to the new Brightspeed experience, while also creating 15 new AEM components to meet design needs.
- Organized a UX workshop with the client, which involved activities like affinity mapping, rose-thorn-buds, user personas/journeys, & competitive analysis to clarify goals and define immediate user and business needs.
- Led the migration of design system from Sketch to Figma, revamped guidelines, font system, color usage, buttons, and components across desktop, tablet, and mobile for consistency & reusability.
- Created mid to high-fidelity prototypes in rapid prototyping sessions to gather user feedback & drive iterative dev.
- Facilitated development meetings to comprehend coding limitations in Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) and provided feedback to streamline component development with time, resource, and development constraints.
- Leveraged Google analytics to track the performance of the product, which showcased a significant boost over **47% increase** in page views, coupled with a **45% increase** in unique pageviews, and a **whopping 70% drop** in bounce rate.
- Led a team of 4 product designers to design a VR experience where users can practice high stress social tasks to build skills and confidence. The initiative was to help CGI venture into XR industries.
- Designed infographics, logos, cover letters and brand elements for the State of Illinois, child welfare (DCFS) program.

### **UX/UI Designer - Softrams LLC.** | March 2019 - April 2022

- Led a team of 2 researchers & designers to design <u>ACO Management System Medicare Shared Savings Program</u>, a healthcare product under the Center of Medicare & Medicaid services (CMS), a federal agency. Designed new modules in the existing system & collaborated with CMS stakeholders to establish product vision and MVP features.
- Re-designed existing modules with UX research methods, also advocated for clear UX writing and 508 compliance testing (accessibility) using wave/web-aim tools. According to the <u>performance results of 2019</u>, ACO-MS had a record year with users saving **\$1.2 billion in Medicare** as compared to **\$739 million** in 2018.
- According to <u>performance results of 2022</u>, there was a significant user growth, with 66 new enrollments & 140 renewals. Over 11 million beneficiaries received care, reflecting a 3% growth of 324k compared to previous year.
- Delivered pixel perfect high-fidelity prototypes for a business contract, which resulted in a \$37 million program.
- Leveraged design thinking & led the research and design of a healthcare SaaS app (<a href="Hdrive">Hdrive</a>) for file sharing and storing. This workflow involved affinity mapping, rose-thorn-buds, user personas/journeys, competitive analysis, user interviews & low to high fidelity prototypes to define and validate user & business needs.

## Web Developer & UX/UI - Carmaguys LLC. (Co-op) | June 2018 - Dec 2018

• Redesigned and developed an appointment & scheduling app for car service and repair startup.

### **Education**

### Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Worcester, MA

Interactive Media and Game Development, Master of Science, 2016 – 2018

• <u>View Master's Thesis</u> - Designed and implemented a car driving simulator to teach driving rules and regulations, incorporating user research, A/B testing, and usability tests to enhance effectiveness and user experience.

### University of Mumbai, India

Computer Engineering, Bachelor of Science, 2011 - 2015

### Design

Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD, InVision, Balsamiq, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Mural, Miro, Optimal Workshop, Google Docs, Miro, SharePoint

#### **Business**

Jira, Confluence, SQL, MS Excel, Salesforce, Power BI, Web analytics (Google Analytics), Pendo, Lucidcharts

### **Development**

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, JavaScript, C#, NodeJS

### Other

Premiere Pro, Maya 3D, Unity Engine, Unreal Engine, VR & Game design

### **Certifications**

- Certified SAFe® 6 Product owner/ Product manager (POPM) certificate
- Certified SAFe® 5 Practitioner certificate
- User experience and interaction for AR/VR/MR/XR Certificate authorized by University of Michigan
- Foundation of user experience (UX) Design Google UX design certificate
- Conduct UX research and test early subjects Google UX design certificate
- Start the UX design process: Empathize, define, ideate Google UX design certificate
- Build wireframes and low-fidelity prototypes Google UX design certificate
- Build Dashboards in Power BI By Coursera

### YouTube channel

- Founded and managed a successful <u>Youtube channel</u> focused on comic characters, demonstrating a strong understanding of the target user's needs and interests.
- Utilized qualitative and quantitative research findings to create captivating content that resonated with viewers, resulting in approximately 3.5 million views and 8 thousand subscribers within just 6 months.
- Conducted comprehensive user research, competitive analysis, and utilized Google analytics to gain insights into audience behavior and optimize content strategy.